<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Quilombist</title><link href="https://quilombist.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://quilombist.github.io/feeds/history.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://quilombist.github.io/</id><updated>2014-11-20T17:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Black Awareness Day in Brazil</title><link href="https://quilombist.github.io/posts/2014/Nov/20/black-awareness-day-in-brazil/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-20T17:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Marcwebbie</name></author><id>tag:quilombist.github.io,2014-11-20:posts/2014/Nov/20/black-awareness-day-in-brazil/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;20 November is Black Awareness Day in Brazil. A day of celebration for the resistence of afro-Brazilians. Today, as always, Brazil white supremacy has strong voice in our education and litterature. Afro-brazilian great symbols are unknown to most Brazilians. Paradoxically, Brazil is the largest black country outside the African continent. A population of about 52% afro-Brazilians and very few, if not none of them, are presented to our children. Black Awareness Day fights to break this strategy of making black people considered slave by&amp;nbsp;nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year black movements in Brazil are lauching a campaign to make Black Awareness day a national holiday in&amp;nbsp;Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zumbi" src="http://www.coladaweb.com/files/zumbi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumbi is considered one of the greatest black heroes in the history of Brazil. But why Zumbi and not the others? Zumbi was the last leader of the Republic of Palmares. The first independent republic in the Americas. In Palmares, blacks, whites and native americas lived in peace and liberty, they were about 30000 people, a very large population by the time. while most of people in colonial Brazil were either illiterate portuguese colonisers or chained&amp;nbsp;africans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="palmares"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Palmares&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At more or less the same time it happened that, very close to our meeting place today, in Angola, the African Queen N’zingha was valiantly resisting, in armed struggle, the invasion of her territories by the&amp;nbsp;Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are only two historic examples out of the long history of resistance and struggle against foreign domination that is an integral part of our African heritage both in the continent and the&amp;nbsp;Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The republic of Palmares, with its immense population by the standards of the epoch, dominated a territorial area more or less one third the size of Portugal. This was the property of all. The fruits of collective labor were the property of all. The free Africans planted and harvested a wide variety of products and bartered with their white and indigenous Brazilian neighbours. They were very effectively both socially and politically, in their African manner and tradition, and were highly skilled in the art of&amp;nbsp;war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palmares put into question the entire colonial structure: the army, the land tenure system of the Portuguese patriachs and the Catholic Church. it withstood some twenty-seven wars of destruction, wageg by both the Portuguese and the Dutch colonial military structures established in Pernambuco. Palmares resister for more than half a&amp;nbsp;century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumbi, the last of Palmares is celebrated in the Pan-African experience of Brazil as the first hero of Pan-Africanism. We hope that he and his people of Palmares will be recognised and remembered by the rest of the Pan-African world as exemplary militants and forefathers of Pan-Africanism&amp;nbsp;itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-major-symbols-of-black-resistence-fights-in-brazil"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some major symbols of black resistence fights in&amp;nbsp;Brazil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dandara&lt;/strong&gt;
Dandara was the Queen of Palmares, military general of Palmares. She refused follow Ganga Zumba on the peace treaty and sided with Zumbi to fight until death and Palmares capital was taken by portuguese forces in&amp;nbsp;1697.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luisa Mahin:&lt;/strong&gt;
Luisa Mahin was the leader of the Revolta dos Malês(Malê Revolt), a black revolt, planned by the islamised slaves in the 19th&amp;nbsp;century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;João Candido:&lt;/strong&gt;
Joao Candido was the leader of the Revolta da Chibata(Revolt of the Lashes). Revolta da chibata was a multi-racial revolt against corporal punishment in the Brazilian navy in 22 November&amp;nbsp;1910.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="national-holiday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;National&amp;nbsp;holiday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of those black brazilians that fought for liberty and justice has a holiday in Brazil. Most of them and not even known to Brazilians, and most of those whove heard about them doesnt even know they were&amp;nbsp;black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-could-we-do-to-facilitate-black-awareness-in-brazil"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What could we do to facilitate black awareness in&amp;nbsp;Brazil?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of all make sure that people recognize they live in a black&amp;nbsp;country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never call the blacks a&amp;nbsp;minority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show them the glory and bravery history of black&amp;nbsp;Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that people understand that Brazil was a country built by africans and not&amp;nbsp;europeans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost every folklore, music, culinary, etc in Brazil was developed by the&amp;nbsp;Africans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain to them that they don&amp;#8217;t see black people on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt; because they are marginalized and&amp;nbsp;inferiorized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show them that brazilian politics have either been a dictature or a democracy lead by either white supremacists or the white dominating&amp;nbsp;minority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fight to make Black Awareness Day a national holiday in&amp;nbsp;Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Above all, help people being proud of being black and proud of being born in a country where their forefathers have&amp;nbsp;built.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumbi está&amp;nbsp;vivo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="history"></category><category term="brazil"></category><category term="zumbi"></category><category term="palmares"></category></entry></feed>